PULKIT AGARWAL

COMPUTER ENGINEER

Dublin, Ireland D08CH2H agarwalp@tcd.ie | +353-872741700

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Portfolio</u> GitHub

Professional Summary

I am a Computer Engineering Graduate with well-developed skills in Android & Web Development and have concluded various projects and certifications in these areas. I have knowledge of various methodologies and tools that are used in fabricating projects in these expanses.

I have had extensive leadership experience within higher education settings with sharp time-management, decision-making, problem-solving and communication skills.

Education

Trinity College Dublin

BAI Computer Engineering

Expected Graduation: **May 2021**Overall Grade (GPA): **II. I**

Relevant Courses: Data Structures & Algorithms, Computer Networks, Software Design Analysis, DBMS, Deep Learning, Integrated Systems Design, Operating Systems, Probability & Statistics, Numerical Analysis. **Technical Skills:** Python, Java, Android Studio, C & C++, SQL, HTML & CSS, Verilog, MATLAB, Linux, Jupyter

Notebook, GitHub.

The Scindia School

AISSCE- Computer Science

High School Completion: March 2016

Percentage: 94.2%

Activities & Societies: School Prefect, Member Student Council, Secretary Academic Council, Vice-Captain Hockey Team, Secretary Inquisitive Society, Secretary Bhabha Scientific Society, Social Service League and Round Square Committee.

Work Experience

Ganesh Plywood Industries - Sitapur, India

April 2017 - August 2019

Associate Database Administrator

- Created Indexes and Views using MySQL to optimize access to multiple Production Tables and initiated the use temp tables along with hints which decreased query response time by 16%.
- A 20% increase in opportunity of creating business relationships with consumers by improving reformat and de-duplication logic.

Volunteer Experience

Trinity College Dublin - Dublin, Ireland

September 2020 - Present

- Mentor at Student2Student (S2S)
 - Strategized and coordinated Student Orientation of more than 25 students at Trinity College Dublin.
 - Sent out weekly emails to my cohort and organized weekly events and meet-ups, which were marketed through social media and emails, to help freshers in their cultural, academic & social transition in college.

The Scindia School - Gwalior, India

April 2015 - March 2016

Secretary, Social Service League

- Volunteered for teaching the kids, constructing a basic drainage system and building a kitchen and library for the government school etc.
- Organized weekly skill shops and regular sports tournaments for the purpose of efficient and holistic growth of people within the community.

Vinnies - Alice Springs, Australia

October - November 2014

Sales Assistant

- Volunteered as a sales-assistant for community services during my Student Cultural Exchange Programme in Australia at St. Stephens' College.
- Described merchandise and explain use, operation, and care of merchandise to customers and addressed all the needs and services requested by the customers.

Projects

Parking Assistance System, Research Project

October 2020 - Present

- This project will explore the design of an 'app' to provide advice to drivers approaching a car park with the goal of smoothing the flow of traffic either to an appropriate (potentially reserved) parking space or away from the area in the case of through or departing traffic.
- Advices will be bases on a model of vehicle coordination using 'slot-based driving' and TDMA in data communication systems to allocate slots to cars (packets) in transit.

Portfolio Website, Personal Project

July - September 2020

- Designed and developed my personal website using my skills in HTML, CSS & Bootstrap and effectively managed time and resources by planning ahead.
- Diagnosed errors and implemented solutions to the problems that occurred while reviewing the website.

Data Fabric Provider, Personal Project

April - May 2020

- Created and deployed a Multi-Client Chat Server in Socket Programming with added functionality of chat privatisation among clients within a server.
- Successfully transformed the data fabric model from a chat server to a file transfer fabric using TCP/IP protocols.

Student-Hub Application, Group Project

January - April 2020

- Used Java to create an Android App that allows users to review notes, set deadlines and rate modules within a college community for academic growth.
- Gained hands-on experience with Java, Android SDK & Git, and tech principles and culture via both team meetings, code reviews and pair programming.

Co-curricular Activities & Awards

Level 1: Trinity Employability Award (Intel), Trinity College Dublin

November 2019

- Learned how to segment problems, ask the right questions, interpret the data and identify solutions using the Model-Based Problem-Solving Process.
- Developed the understanding of the business need for problem-solving as technology becomes more complex.

P. M. Khar Trophy, The Scindia School

February 2016

 Awarded annually to one student for their encouraging pursuit for science through various measuring prospects.

Umang Mathur Award, The Scindia School

October 2015

• One of the most prestigious honour, awarded annually to one student for best academic proficiency in the following academic term.

Sam Pitroda Award, The Scindia School

October 2015

- Instrumented a project called as the flame tube to show transverse nature of sound waves.
- Awarded annually to the most innovative science project in the following academic term.

International Student Exchange. St. Philips' College Australia

October 2014

- Propelled towards acceptance and understanding of an array of different cultural and community perspectives developing a cultivated global mindset.
- Adopted alternative, multi-faceted approaches of learning and language acquisition through practical immersion.

References

References are available upon request.